When building a machinery model,
we want our model to generalize as well as possible.
Let's consider the following example.
In the first case,
shown by the graph on the left,
we fit a linear regression model to our dataset as shown by the blue line.
In the other case,
shown on the right,
we use a polynomial regression model which is
a much more complex machine learning model
and we observed that this model fits the data precisely.
However, how do you think each model is going to perform on new data?.
The linear regression model will better perform on
this new data because it's not fitting the original data as closely.
We will say that this model generalizes well to new data.
However, the polynomial regression model will not perform well on the new data.
We'll use the term overfitting to describe this behavior.
The challenge of machine learning lies in creating
a model that performs well on the available data without overfitting.
We'll cover these in depth in later sections.
From now on, we will use the term Training datasets to describe
the data that our models have been trained on and the term Test dataset
to describe data that has not been used during training.
We'll use the test dataset to solve this overfitting issue.
In the following videos,
we'll describe how to create such datasets.